openlogic.com 2018-06-16

# Privacy Policy | Rogue Wave

Last updated: May 11, 2018

This Privacy Policy (or "Policy") describes the ways in which Rogue Wave Software (together with its affiliates "Company" or "we") collect, use, process, and disclose information that we collect from you or that you may provide when you visit any website on which this Policy is posted. We may have different policies for other sites and products, so please always check for the applicable policy on any of our sites you may use. Also, please note that this Policy does not apply to information collected by us offline or through any other means, including when you use one of our products or services, unless we tell you that it applies at the time we collect or use your information.

Please read this Policy carefully before sharing information with us. By using the website on which this Policy is posted, you agree to the terms of this Policy and our use, sharing and disclosure of information as described below including any revisions to this Policy. If you do not agree with the practices described in this Policy, you may choose not to use this website. In the event of any conflict between this Policy and either (1) a specific contract we have with you, if any; (2) applicable law, the terms of items (1) and (2) will control over this Policy, and this Policy shall be deemed amended to conform to such other items.

## Information we may collect about you and how we collect it

We collect two kinds of information, **personal information** that can be used to identify you, and **non-personal** information.

Non-personal information is information that does not identify you as an individual person. Like other companies, Rogue Wave collects certain non-personal information about visitors to its websites. This includes information about your internet connection, your IP address, the equipment you use to access our website, usage details, and search queries submitted on our website.

We also may collect non-personal information automatically as you navigate through the site through the use of technology such as cookies, flash cookies, and web beacons. Using this kind of technology, our web servers automatically recognize and collect the domain name and IP address of visitors to our website. This kind of technology may transfer data to your browser that can be read by us as a sort of a non-personal identification card, recording information about your past visits to our website. In addition, we collect aggregate information on web page visits.

Personal information is information that identifies you as an individual person. We collect personal information when you voluntarily share it with us, for instance, when you do business with us, when you inquire about our products and services, or when you apply for a job with us. In each of these situations, we may collect personal information that includes your name, address, phone number, email address, job title, company name and company contact information (and for job applicants, your qualifications and work history). Note that Rogue Wave has separate policies and notices that apply to employees' personal data once they are hired and this Policy does not apply to employee data. If you purchase a product on our web store, we collect payment information. Please note, we do not store any payment or credit card information. We only use payment information in connection with the purchase of Rogue Wave products.

## How we use the information we collect

We may use non-personal information for any reason. We may use your personal information for our legitimate purposes and for any purposes we disclose to you at the time of collection, including processing it to respond to your requests. Our uses of your personal information may include processing to:

  * Present the website and its content to you;
  * Provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us and optimize your experience on our website;
  * Provide customer support, permit product evaluations, or otherwise manage our relationship with you or your company, including responding to your requests and providing you with service
  * Notify you about changes to our website or any products or services we offer;
  * Communicate with you by e-mail, postal mail, telephone, or mobile device about our products, services, industry issues, and upcoming events;
  * Perform research and analysis about your use of, or interest in, our products, services, or website;
  * Update and improve our products and services;
  * Perform other functions as otherwise described to you at the time of collection; and
  * Recruit and hire job applicants and process applications, communicate with the applicants, and fulfill legal or regulatory requirements, if necessary.

## Disclosure of your information

We may disclose or share your information, including personal information:

  * With our subsidiaries and affiliated companies, companies with which we have a strategic relationship;
  * With other companies that perform work necessary for Rogue Wave (but only to allow them to provide products and services for us);
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information;
  * To a successor, if all or part of our business is sold, merged, dissolved, acquired, reorganized or subject to a similar transaction; and
  * As necessary to comply with a subpoena or similar investigative demand, court order, request for cooperation from law enforcement or other governmental agency, to exercise our legal rights, to defend against legal claims, to protect someone's safety, or as otherwise required by law.

## Your choices about collection and use of your information

You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but that may result in you being unable to use certain features of our website, request information about products or services, apply for a job, purchase products and services, ask questions, or initiate other transactions on our website. You also can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to accept or reject it. And you can opt out of receiving future emails from us (other than emails that are necessary communications depending on the nature of our relationship with you) by clicking the "unsubscribe" link in any email you receive from us. We also have a preference center to indicate your areas of interest and to control our outreach to you.

## How we protect your personal information

We take appropriate security measures (including physical, technical, and administrative measures) to help safeguard your personal information from unauthorized access and disclosure. No system, however, can be completely secure. While we take steps to secure your personal information, we do not promise that your personal information, searches, or other questions will always remain secure. We are not responsible or liable for the illegal acts (such as hacking) by third parties. If you have concerns about the security of your personal information, please contact us at privacy@roguewave.com.

## Links to other sites

Our websites may contain links to the sites of other companies. Rogue Wave is not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of those companies before sharing information.

## Children's privacy

Our website is a general audience site and is not directed at, or intended for use by, children under 13. Accordingly, we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

## Accessing and updating your information

The accuracy of your information is important to us. If you change your email address, or if any of the other information we hold about you is inaccurate or out of date, please contact us at info@roguewave.com to update your information. If you are located in certain jurisdictions, you have the right to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you or other rights as set forth in applicable law. We reserve the right to limit or deny access to personal information where providing such access is unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances or as otherwise permitted by applicable law. Additional rights of E.U. data subjects' are explained below.

## European data subjects' rights

If you reside in the European Union, the "General Data Protection Regulation" provides you with certain rights. You may request information regarding whether we are processing your personal information, our purposes in doing so, how we obtained your personal information (if you did not provide it directly), who we may have been shared with, and how long we will be retained. Further, you have the right to request that we correct your personal information if the information is inaccurate and, in certain circumstances, may ask us to erase the information or stop using your personal information. Finally, subject to certain limitations and when feasible, you may request that we provide you with a copy of your personal information or transfer it to another controller. If we feel we must deny this request, we will provide an explanation. Otherwise, to the extent feasible, we will provide you with a copy of your personal information within a reasonable amount of time.

Additional information on your rights under the General Data Protection Regulation is available from the U.K.'s Information Commissioner's Office. If you have a concern about the way we process your personal information, you may have the right to make a complaint to the appropriate data protection authority in the E.U.

Please note, as indicated below, your personal information may be transferred to servers in the United States.

## Data transfer, storage, and retention

Rogue Wave has customers located around the world. In order to ensure you receive the highest quality products and services, it may be necessary to transfer your information to a country outside the country where it was originally collected. Rogue Wave stores your personal information on its servers and on the servers of cloud-based service providers with whom Rogue Wave contracts. Some of those servers are located in the United States. You understand and agree that information you provide may be sent to and processed by Rogue Wave affiliates and companies that perform services for us on computers located in jurisdictions other than the one in which you are based, including in the United States. The data protection laws in these countries may not be the same as the data protection laws in your home country.

Rogue Wave retains personal data we collect from as long as necessary to service our corporate clients or process a job application. If you have questions regarding Rogue Wave's retention of your information, please contact the representative identified at the end of this Policy.

## Changes to this Policy

If there are updates to this Policy, we will post those changes here and update the revision date so you will always know what information we collect, how we use it, and what choices you have. Continued use of this website after any changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes. Accordingly, we encourage you to check the Policy periodically for updates. Please note that this Policy was changed on May 11, 2018 to better enable customers to understand how personal information is collected, used and shared.

## Do not track

We do not respond to **"do-not-track"** signals or other mechanisms that allow users to signal their preferences on the collection of their personal information over time and across third-party websites or online services. This website does not monitor for or adjust any use as the result of "do-not-track" signals.

## How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Policy or our information-handling practices, please contact us at [privacy@roguewave.com](mailto:privacy@roguewave.com).
